We all know that factory farms are
terrible but what about eating animals
that come from free range farms or from hunting?
If all we succeeded at was
stopping the factory farms I'd be so
happy. Because an animal that is
living in a natural environment and
really getting to experience its
sovereignty and its direction of its
life and then gets killed hopefully quickly,
it's a radically different experience
than an animal
that is really enslaved and enslaved
in poor to terrible to atrocious
conditions for its whole life and then killed in
very often a very brutal way. If
we only made that shift that would be so
humongous. So much of the atrocity
would be addressed.
Then the question comes, is that the only
shift worth making?
Is that all the shift? For me as much respect as I have for
the Native American kind of ethic, I
also notice that
in areas where there was more
pre-agriculture, in areas where there was
more natural edible plant life,
there was less animal consumption. And in
areas where there is less natural, edible
plant life there was more animal
consumption because that's what the people had to
do to adapt and live there.
We totally understand. Post-agriculture, were we have the ability to grow
everything we need plant-wise, then
if that produces less suffering,
less less harm than killing more
sentient creatures,
then is there really a justification for
continuing the animal thing? For me there isn't.
We talk about the idea of humane
slaughter
and it really is an oxymoron and all you
have to do to recognize that is ask,
would you be okay being on the other
side of it?
In morality there's a famous test
called the pie slice theorem.
Is something really ethical, is
something fair? It's like
you slice the pie, you pick what the two sides are,
and I get to pick which one
I want, or I slice and you pick, but that way we avoid bias.
We need to ask, are we setting up a dynamic for how we
tend to animals where we would be okay being in their position and if the answer is no,
I wouldn't want to live for I was
taken care of pretty well
and then murdered quickly, then the
answer is they wouldn't want that either
and if it was necessary then we have to
look at justifying it but if it's not
necessary there's really no
justification for it.
That really is the key, to get
is that no animal has ever voluntarily
but their head on the chopping block and
if they knew that was coming would do
everything in their power to get away from it
and just because we have the power to
take their life away do we have the right?
And if we need to,
you know if there's a situation where we
are in a survival situation, we have no
other resources and we're going to die or they're going to die,
it's a totally different story. If someone really didn't know how to be
healthy otherwise it's a different story.
But if it's simply a preference for us
but it's
the whole possibility for life for them them,
then I don't think we can ethically justify that.
I think it's something that you find consistent through all forms of life,
from the most complex to the most basic, is that every
animal wants to live, at the end of the
day
there isn't any animal that doesn't want
it
to have placed and to experience life
what its
it's a fundamental impulse apply for
biology is to continue writing to
propagate in
I'm and we think about are
desires everything we wanted everything
we don't want to talk contingent
upon life right and without that
everything else is gone so
it is Adam other their children and to
be social and two
experience anything that one experience
is
on the foundation of their ability to
live in such take that away
for just I like the way it tastes right
or something that is
so surface in our hierarchy of needs
and it's at the core at their hierarchy
of needs means that we have to make
their life so unimportant in our eyes
did their whole right to life is worth
less than something
relatively trivial to us and if we're
willing to take another feeling life
forms and me make
their whole experience that trivial then
there's a bleed over affect where we
start doing that with other people
right we start doing that with anything
else we start thinking of
the restive life as a commodity for us
rather than
other sovereign life under their own
right to life we're not thinking about
what is it what is it what does it feel
what is a trait like how can I support
it having a full life experience in this
universe it's
what is in it for me and even if it
requires harming it hurting it how can I
get what I want out of it
we start thinking that way in the area
it leads to way of thinking that leads
over
to commoditized in all life we can see
that being like an
underlying way and bean
for all the problems in the world right
now